Guide to the Stratemeyer Syndicate Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Stratemeyer Syndicate records
1895-1987
GEN MSS 107
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9.25
(13 boxes)
The Stratemeyer Syndicate Records consist of legal and financial documents, letters, and notebooks which record the operations of some aspects of the syndicate from the 1960s to 1984, and the sale of the publishing concern in 1984.
Stratemeyer Syndicate
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Stratemeyer Syndicate Records were donated to the Beinecke Library in 1992 by Nancy S. Axelrad.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
STRATEMEYER SYNDICATE
The Stratemeyer Syndicate, a publishing concern that generated several well-known series of children's fiction books during the 20th century, was incorporated by Edward Stratemeyer in 1910. Stratemeyer, born in 1862 in Elizabeth, New Jersey, began writing stories for magazines while working in his own stationery store in the 1880s. He married in 1891, and in 1892, the year his daughter Harriet was born, he sold fourteen dime novels and five magazine stories. He continued his work by contributing to the Nick Carter series of stories and eventually had a popular boys' novel, Under Dewey at Manila, published in 1898. After completing several manuscripts left by the late authors William T. Adams and Horatio Alger, Stratemeyer began his own first series of novels for boys. His Rover Boys adventures, which began to appear in 1899, were brisk sellers. In 1906, he started the Bobbsey Twins series using the pseudonym Laura Lee Hope. He followed this success with several more series, including the immensely popular Tom Swift in 1910, the year he incorporated his business officially as the Stratemeyer Syndicate.
As Stratemeyer began to capture much of the new market for boys' and girls' fiction at the turn of the century, he started to contract out most of his stories to ghostwriters who filled out general plot outlines he had scripted. In 1927, the Hardy Boys made their first appearance and shortly before his death in 1930, Edward Stratemeyer sketched a new heroine named Nancy Drew. Stratemeyer's daughter, Harriet Adams, completed work on the first Nancy Drew adventure and eventually wrote so many of the Nancy Drew mysteries that she became closely identified with the pseudonymous Carolyn Keene, the "author" of the series. Adams headed the Syndicate, which became a limited partnership with three or four active contributing partners at any one time.
The popularity of various Syndicate characters grew. Nancy Drew films appeared in the 1930s; the Hardy Boys appeared in the 1950s in serialized adventures on Walt Disney's Mickey Mouse Club; both Nancy Drew and Joe and Frank Hardy were featured in a mid-1970s television series produced by Universal Television. During the 1960s and 1970s, efforts were made to update several of the older, dated volumes in the Stratemeyer series. Together with the introduction of more modern dress and situations, Nancy Drew, the Hardy Boys, and the Happy Hollisters retained an uncomplicated demeanor while appealing to a new generation of juvenile readers.
Harriet Adams was feted in 1980 for her success as the writer of Nancy Drew. She died two years later, on March 27, 1982, leaving three partners to carry on the work of the Syndicate. In 1984, the rights to all creations of the Stratemeyer Syndicate were purchased by Simon & Schuster, which has continued to produce series such as Nancy Drew and the Bobbsey Twins.
Scope and Contents
The Stratemeyer Syndicate Records contain legal and financial documents, letters, printed materials, photographs, notebooks, and realia which trace the workings of the publishing concern up to the point at which it was sold to Simon & Schuster in 1984. The Records span the dates 1895-1987, with the majority of materials created in 1984.
The collection is housed in 13 boxes and consists of six series: Legal Documents, Financial Documents, Correspondence, Other Papers, Printed Materials, and Notebooks. Boxes 11-13 contain Oversize material.
Series I, Legal Documents spans the years 1895-1985. The first subseries holds General material from individuals and organizations having legal dealings with the Stratemeyer Syndicate. Extant in the Universal and Walt Disney files are contracts for the development of television shows based on Stratemeyer characters (Box 1, folders 15-18 and folder 19). Writers' agreements files contain examples of contracts executed between the Syndicate and contributing ghostwriters 1895-1984 (Box 1, folders 21-38). The second subseries, Simon & Schuster, which forms the bulk of the entire collection, documents the 1984 sale of partnership interests and rights to Simon Schuster. The first item in this subseries is the final volume of papers detailing the arrangements of the purchase (Box 2, folders 39-44). An index is found in folder 39. Following this final version of the sale document are drafts of most of its individual sections, arranged in the order in which they appear in the final volume. For certain documents which have several drafts, attempts have been made to place them in probable order of their creation. Unique descriptions have been made where possible, though certain items (e.g. Box 3, folders 75 and 76) are distinguished only by folder order. These drafts are followed by assorted items related to Simon & Schuster's purchase of the Stratemeyer Syndicate. Among these are lists of subcontracting licenses, trademark assignments, and internal memos from the law firm which handled the sale.
Series II, Financial Documents, contains items such as billing statements and financial worksheets spanning the dates 1975-85. A number of items relate to the sale to Simon & Schuster, such as financial statements from the Stratemeyer Syndicate (Box 6, folder 176) and lists of the distribution of proceeds from the sale (Box 6, folder 258). Financial documents from agreements with Grosset & Dunlap and billed audit trails for services provide by the law firm of Finley, Kunble, Wagner, Heine, Underberg, Manley & Casey are also included.
Series III, Correspondence, consists of a small number of letters to and from the Stratemeyer Syndicate together with a bound volume of closing correspondence relating to the sale to Simon and Schuster. (Box 7, folder 188).
Series IV, Other Papers, contains various materials related to the operation of the Stratemeyer Syndicate prior to the 1984 purchase by Simon & Schuster. The manuscripts section includes speeches by Harriet Adams (Folders 204-06), an outline of a play concerning Nancy Drew by Steven Angel (Folder 207) and a typescript history of the Stratemeyer Syndicate (Folder 208). Authorship lists (Folder 259) for the Bobbsey Twins, the Hardy Boys, and Nancy Drew series provide information on who wrote the plots and the texts for many of these books. Also included are photographs of Harriet Adams and two dictation machines used by Adams to record Nancy Drew stories.
Series V, Printed Materials, consists of newspaper and magazine clippings and copies of magazines on various subjects, such as Nancy Drew (Box 9, folder 238) and the history of the Stratemeyer Syndicate (Box 9, folders 247-48) dating between 1923-86.
Series VI, Notebooks, contains notebooks compiled by Nancy Axelrad.
Oversize materials from Series II, IV and V are housed in Boxes 11-13.
Received with the materials listed above were 31 audiocassettes which have been transferred to Historical Sound Recordings in Sterling Memorial Library.
This collection complements other Stratemeyer Syndicate materials located in the Betsy Beinecke Shirley Collection of American Children's Literature.
Adventure stories -- History and criticism; Bobbsey Twins (Fictitious characters); Children's literature in series; Children's literature -- Publishing -- United States; Children's stories, American -- History and criticism; Detective and mystery stories -- History and criticism; Drew, Nancy (Fictitious character); Hardy Boys (Fictitious characters); Swift, Tom (Fictitious character); Authors; Adams, Harriet Stratemeyer; Axelrad, Nancy S.; Stratemeyer, Edward, 1862-1930; Simon and Schuster, Inc; Stratemeyer Syndicate
- Legal Documents, 1895-1985; Series I; 2; (5 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Legal Documents is divided into 2 subseries. General materials are arranged alphabetically by name or document type. The Simon and Schuster subseries begins with a bound volume of closing documents and is followed by drafts of these documents filed in the order in which they appear in the final volume. Following these are Other Papers arranged alphabetically by name or subject.
  - General
    - Axelrad, Nancy: Stratemeyer partnership, 1976 Mar 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Copyrights and trademarks, 1906-83 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Financing statements, 1976-84 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Foreign contracts, 1951-84 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Grosset and Dunlap, 1931-83 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Office lease, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Partnership agreement, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Permission statements, 1951-76, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Scholastic, 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Squier, Edna: employment contract, 1949 Apr (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Stratemeyer, Magdelene; rights transfer, 1931 Jun 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Termination statements, 1981, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Universal television, 1976, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15-18)
    - Walt Disney Productions, 1955-59 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Wanderer Books, 1979-84 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Writers's agreements
      - Adams, Harriet, 1976, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Axelrad, Nancy, 1977, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - "A" general, 1955, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - "B" general, 1959-84 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - "C-D" general, 1905-60 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - DiVono, Sharman
        Related Archival Materials note
        See: William Rotsler, Box 1, folder 34
      - Frame, Paul, 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - "F" general, 1921-78 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Garis, Howard L., 1906-38 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        See also: W. B. Foster, Box 1, folder 27
      - Garis, Lilian, 1909-48 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Grote, Grace, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Jessup, Dorothea, 1955 Jul 15 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - "L" general, 1979, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Messman, Jon, 1982 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Prager, Arthur, 1973 Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Rotsler, William, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Stratemeyer, Edward, 1925 Oct 5 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Stratemeyer, L. C., 1895 Dec 17 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - "S" general, 1971, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "W" general, 1906-74 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Blank forms, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Simon & Schuster
    - Transactions of Purchase
      - Final bound volume, 1984 Jul 31 (Box 2, Folder 39-44)
      - Index; drafts, 1984 Jul (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Assignment of partnership interests; drafts, 1984 Jul (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Grant termination; drafts, 1984 Jul (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Termination of transfer; drafts, 1984 Jul (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Assignment of reverted rights; drafts, 1984 Jul (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Assignment of renewal and reversionary rights, 1984 Jul (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Purchase agreement
        - Draft, 1984 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 51)
        - Draft, 1984 Jun 13 (Box 2, Folder 52)
        - Draft, 1984 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 53)
        - Draft: annotated by Jeffery Konvitz, 1984 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 54)
        - Draft: annotated by Mark Teitelbaum, 1984 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 55)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 19 (Box 2, Folder 56)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul 19 (Box 2, Folder 57)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 2, Folder 58)
        - Draft: redlined, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 59)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 60)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 31 (Box 3, Folder 61)
        - Drafts: redlined, 1984 Jul 31 (Box 3, Folder 62)
        - Signed copy, 1984 Jul 31 (Box 3, Folder 63)
        - Draft, variant pages, 1984 Jul 31 (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - Schedule of Exceptions
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 65)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 66)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 67)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul 17 (Box 3, Folder 68)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul 17 (Box 3, Folder 69)
        - Draft pages: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 70)
        - Draft page: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 71)
        - Draft pages: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 72)
        - Draft pages, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 73)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 74)
        - Draft pages: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 75)
        - Draft pages: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 76)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 77)
        - Draft pages: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - Schedule of U.S. works
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 79)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 3, Folder 80)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 81)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 82)
        - Draft pages, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 83)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 84)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 26 (Box 4, Folder 85)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 4, Folder 86)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul (Box 4, Folder 87)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul (Box 4, Folder 88)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 4, Folder 89)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul 30 (Box 4, Folder 90)
        - Notes, 1984 Jul (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - Schedule of foreign works
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul 24 (Box 4, Folder 92)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 4, Folder 93)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul 26 (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - Schedule of U.S. copyrights
        - Copy: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 95)
        - Addendum: draft, annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 96)
        - Addendum: draft, annotated (Box 5, Folder 97)
        - Addendum: draft, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 98)
        - Addendum: draft, annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 99)
        - Addendum: draft, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 100)
        - Corrections, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 101)
        - Notes, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 102)
        - Computer Cards, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - Schedule of U.S. books missing
        - Drafts, 1984 Jul 25 (Box 5, Folder 104)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul 27 (Box 5, Folder 105)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 106)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul 30 (Box 5, Folder 107)
        - Draft, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 108)
        - Notes, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 109)
        - Computer cards, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 110)
      - Series titles list
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 111)
        - OCR scanning form, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 112)
        - Draft: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 113)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 114)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul 26 (Box 5, Folder 115)
        - Drafts: annotated, 1984 Jul 30 (Box 5, Folder 116)
      - Axelrad, Nancy, employment contract: (Box 5, Folder 117)
        - drafts, 1984 Jul
      - Assignment and assumption of lease, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 118)
      - General release: copy, 1984 Jul 31 (Box 5, Folder 119)
      - Assignment of rights by partners: draft, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 120)
      - Instrument of transfer: draft, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 121)
      - Trademark and related rights assignment: draft, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 122)
      - Assignment of Grosset and Dunlap agreements: draft and signed copy, 1984 Aug-Sep (Box 5, Folder 123)
      - Lists of schedules and exhibits: annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 124)
      - Schedule of closing documents: drafts, annotated, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Related Papers
      - Angel, Dennis: releases, 1984 Mar 13 (Box 5, Folder 126)
      - Argentina trademarks, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 127)
      - Axelrad, Nancy
        - Book contract, 1984-85 (Box 5, Folder 128)
        - Release: drafts, 1985 Jan (Box 5, Folder 129)
      - Books in progress, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 130)
      - Cover letters, miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 131)
      - Domestic book club contracts list, 1984 Jun 28 (Box 5, Folder 132)
      - List of files received from Nancy Axelrad, 1984 Aug 15 (Box 5, Folder 133)
      - Foreign contracts list, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 134)
      - Foreign literary agents, 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 135)
      - Memos, 1984-85 (Box 5, Folder 136)
      - Notes, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 137)
      - Series production lists, 1979-84 (Box 5, Folder 138)
      - Stratemeyer agenda, 1984 Jun 6 (Box 5, Folder 139)
      - Sublicensing contracts list, 1984 Jun 28 (Box 5, Folder 140)
      - Trademark assignments, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 141)
      - Trademark registration list, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 142)
      - U.S. copyright claimants, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 143)
- Financial Documents, 1975-85; Series II; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series II, Financial Documents, is arranged alphabetically by name, then by type of document.
  - Finley, Kumble, Wagner, Heine, Underberg, Manley & Casey
    - Billed Audit Trails
      - California, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 144)
      - Copyright, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 145)
      - Ennslin & Liablin, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 146)
      - General, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 147)
      - Grosset & Dunlap, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 148)
      - Huron Theatre Lawsuit, 1983 Aug 20 (Box 6, Folder 149)
      - Infocom, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 150)
      - Kid Stuff, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 151)
      - Tom Swift, 1983 Dec 24 (Box 6, Folder 152)
      - Trademark, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 153)
      - Universal TV, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 154)
      - Wanderer Books, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Billing memorandum
      See: Oversize, Box 11, folder 257
    - Client billing and payment history
    - Disbursement of escrow funds
      - Form, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 156)
  - Grosset & Dunlap
    - Overpayment and discount computations, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Statement of royalty, 1983 Jun 30 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Statement of royalty, 1983 Dec 31 (Box 6, Folder 159)
  - Insurance Coverage
    - Insurance, 1984-85 (Box 6, Folder 160)
  - Pitney Bowes
    - Equipment agreements, 1982-83 (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Simon & Schuster
    - Accounts payable
      See: Oversize, Box 11, folder 258
    - Advance monies request, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Amounts deposited schedule, 1984 Jul 19 (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - Artwork reimbursement, 1981-84 (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - Bills and Receipts
      - Aaron Priest Agency, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 165)
      - Eyler, Gordon M., 1984 Sep 4 (Box 6, Folder 166)
      - Grosset & Dunlap, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 167)
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-85 (Box 6, Folder 168)
      - Rental, 1984-85 (Box 6, Folder 169)
      - Warner Bros., 1984 Nov (Box 6, Folder 170)
      - See also: Grosset & Dunlap, Box 6, folder 148
    - Checks written schedule, 1984 Jul 19 (Box 6, Folder 171)
    - Cumulative earnings: Books written by Nancy Axelrad, 1975-84 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Disbursements from sale of partnership, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Distribution of proceeds of sale of partnership
    - Domestic royalties paid, 1981-84 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Escrow balance, 1985 Jan 8 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Financial statements: Stratemeyer Syndicate, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Licensing arrangements, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Miscellaneous addendum, 1984 Jul 25 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Partnership interests, projected gains, 1984 Apr 24 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Payments due from Stratemeyer, 1983-84 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Proceeds available from sale of partnership
    - Royalties receivable
- Correspondence, 1932-85; Series III; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series III, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Gallagher, Richard, 1973 Mar 27 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Horatio Alger Society, 1978, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Liepman AG [publisher], 1984 Jan 3 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Lindblom, Norwood, 1985 Feb5 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - LMI Ltd., 1983 Nov 28 (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - Marks, Mariann, 1980 Mar 4 (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - Mother's Day Council, Inc., 1979 Apr 17 (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - Potter, Andrew, 1956 Apr 5 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Putnam Pub. Co., 1984 Feb 21 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Radzminski, Wayne, 1982 Mar 11 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - R & B Realty, 1984 Nov 5 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Simon & Schuster
    - Closing correspondence [bound], 1983-84 (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - General, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Squier, Wesley C., Mrs., 1955 Dec 14 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Svenson, Edna C., 1932 Apr 28 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Universal Studios, 1978-84 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Wanderer Books, 1983-84 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Warner Bros., 1984 Dec (Box 7, Folder 193)
- Other Papers, 1927-87; Series IV; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series IV, Other Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of document, then by author or title.
  - Authorship lists
    Bobbsey Twins
    See: Oversize, Box 11, folder 259
    Hardy Boys
    Nancy Drew
  - Biographical notes
    - Karig, Walter, 1954, 1956, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Stratemeyer, Edward, 1954, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Bookstore survey, 1982, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Character card file list, 1984 Jun 19 (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Dictation machines
    See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 261 and Box 13, folder 262
  - Engagement calendars: Harriet Adams, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 198-99)
  - Flyers
    - Little Orchestra Society, 1980 Mar 1 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Macy's, 1980 Feb 16 (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - Hardy Boys books list, 1927-72 (Box 8, Folder 202)
  - Invitations, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Manuscripts
    Adams, Harriet
    - "Luncheon speech, Wellesley Club": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Wellesley speech: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - "Yakima speech": typescript, corrected, 1974 May 4 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Angel, Steven: "Nancy Drew - Outline": typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Gallagher, Richard: "Richard Stratemeyer: a Cultural History": typescript, photocopy, [1974] (Box 8, Folder 208-209)
      Accompanied by copy of letter from Harriet S. Adams to Richard Gallagher, 1974 Oct 9 [gift of Richard Gallagher, 2003]
    - JLA: Biographical data on Harriet Adams: typescript, corrected, [1980?] (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Unidentified: "Stratemeyer Syndicate": typescript (Box 8, Folder 211)
  - Notes
    - Adams, Harriet, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Miscellaneous, [1984?] (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - Photographs
    - With Nancy Axelrad in the Garden of Gethsemane, Jerusalem, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - At Nancy Drew 50th anniversary puppet show, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Portraits, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - Press releases, 1984, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Programs
    - Adams, Harriet; memorial service, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - "Music, Stories and Puppets", 1980 Feb (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - Wellesley College Alumnae Achievement awards, 1978 Mar 3 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Zonta Club in honor of Harriet Adams, 1978 Apr 17 (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Signature sheet of Stratemeyer pseudonyms, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - Timetable, 1981-86 (Box 8, Folder 223)
- Printed Material, 1923-86; Series V; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series IV is arranged alphabetically by subject heading or title of publication.
  - Adams, Harriet
    - Doll collection, 1979 Jan (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - Obituaries, 1982 Mar-Apr (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - Post-death remembrances, 1982 Mar-Apr (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Profiles, 1971-82 (Box 9, Folder 227)
      See also: Oversize, Box 11, folder 260